// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
    {
    numb: 1,
    question: "The largest circular storm in our solar system is on the surface of which planet?",
    answer: "Jupiter",
    options: [
      "Jupiter",
      "Venus",
      "Uranus",
      "Earth"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "The biggest asteroid is known as ?",
    answer: "Ceres",
    options: [
      "Vesta",
      "Icarus",
      "Ceres",
      "Eros"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "Rounded to the nearest day,the Mercurian year is equal to ?",
    answer: "88 days",
    options: [
      "111 days",
      "88 days",
      "50 days",
      "25 days"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "One of the largest volcanos in our solar system-if not the largest-is named Olympus Mons. This volcano is located on .",
    answer: "Mars",
    options: [
      "Jupiter's moon Callisto",
      "Venus",
      "Saturn's moon Titan",
      "Mars"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "One Jupiter day is equal to the ",
    answer: "9 hrs 50 min",
    options: [
      "30 hrs 40 min",
      "9 hrs 50 min",
      "3 hrs 20 min",
      "52 hrs 10 min"
    ]
  },
  
   {
     numb: 6,
     question: "The time interval between two successive occurrences of a specific type of alignment of a planet (or the moon) with the sun and the earth is referred to as .",
     answer: "A synodic period",
    options: [
       "A conjunction",
       "An opposition",
       "A sidereal period",
       "A synodic period"
     ]
   },
   
   {
      numb: 7,
     question: "Of the following four times, which one best represents the time it takes energy generated in the core of the sun to reach the surface of the sun and be radiated.",
     answer: "One million years",
    options: [
       "Three minutes",
       "Thirty days",
       "One thousand years",
       "One million years"
     ]
   },
   { numb: 8,
     question: "The sunspot cycle is of :",
     answer: "11 years",
    options: [
       "3 years",
       "11 years",
       "26 years",
       "49 years"
     ]
   },
   {
   numb: 9,
     question: "The Hertzsprung-Russel Diagram of stars DIRECTLY compares what TWO of the following properties of stars.",
     answer: "Temperature and luminosity",
    options: [
       "Temperature and luminosity",
       "Size and Temperature",
       "Luminosity and density",
       "Size and density"
     ]
   },
   {
   numb: 10,
     question: "The andromeda Galaxy is which of the following types of galaxies.",
     answer: "Spiral",
    options: [
       "Elliptical",
       "Spiral",
       "Barred-spiral",
       "Irregular"
     ]
   },
];